A Calendar of The Jefferson Papers of the University of Virginia
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series I: Dated Materials
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON LEASE OF SHADWELL TO CRAVEN PEYTON., 1799 October 1.; ADS. 2 pp.; Barrow. Owned by Office of Clerk of Albemarle County Court. #5145. Printed: Betts, Farm Book, 166-68.
    Witnessed by James Dinsmore, Robert Bolling, and Richard Richardson. Mentions Monticello.
    [2577]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON LEASE OF SHADWELL to CRAVEN PEYTON., 1799 October 1.; ADS. 2 pp.; Barrow. Letterpress copy. Endorsed by T. J. #12436. Original MS. owned by C. S. Hutter, Jr.
    Lease for a part of Shadwell for five years, the rent to be paid in gold or silver money. No field to be sown in corn more than one year; each field to lie fallow or be sown in peas or clover for two years. Witnessed by Robert Bolling, James Densmore, and Richard Richardson.
    [638]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to STEPHEN T. MASON., 1799 October 27.; L. 1 pp. #38-414-a. Extract by N. P. Trist, ca. 1830. Printed: Ford VII 379-399.
    Congratulations on [Thomas] McKean's election [as Governor of Pennsylvania]. Republican party in Pennsylvania. Reformation of Congress at least two years away. Protagonists of England and France in Congress.
    [639]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to CHARLES PINCKNEY., 1799 October 29.; L. 1 pp. #38-414-a. Extract by N. P. Trist, ca. 1830. Printed: Ford VII 379-399; B of R VI 371 (MS. in DLC).
    Oliver Ellsworth and James Iredell working toward a monarchy through common law doctrine. Washington's attitude. French misfortunes and British aggressions.
    [640]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Albemarle County, to [?]., 1799 November 28.; ANS. 1 pp. McGregor Library, #4898.
    John Haden to guide Chickasaw Indians to see Governor in Richmond.
    [2578]
  - JOHN BRECKINRIDGE, Frankfort, Ky., to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1799 December 13.; L. 1 pp. #38-414-a. Extract for N. P. Trist, ca. 1830. Printed: B of R VIII 68 (MS. in DLC).
    Kentucky Resolutions. Popular opposition to the Alien and Sedition laws.
    [641]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to JOHN WAYLES EPPES., 1799 December 21.; ALS. 1 pp.; silked; repair and loss of text on upper right corner. #38-576.
    [William] Woods defeated Peter Carr in election. [Wilson C.?] Nicholas and T. J. delayed by snow. News of Eppes' slaves. Agrees to engage Powell (as overseer?). Reference to Mr. and Mrs. Francis Eppes.
    [642]
  - JAMES L. HENDERSON. DEED to TUCKER M. WOODSON., 1799 December 28.; D. 4 pp.; Barrow. Endorsed by T. J. and others. McGregor Library, #564.
    Conveying his share of Bennett Henderson's estate, excepting his interest in a mill and a lot and house in Milton. Witnessed by Marbell Camden, William Gambill, and Bennett [H.] Henderson. John Henderson's bond for James Henderson's performance of contract, 28 December 1799, witnessed by Thomas Concord and John Agg. Woodson's assignment of his title to Craven Peyton, 25 April 1801, witnessed by Samuel H. Woodson and Bred. Gaines. (See letter from Jefferson to Peyton regarding purchase of Woodson's share 15 January 1801).
    [643]
  - JAMES MADISON to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1799 December 29.; L. 1 pp. Extract. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    On same sheet as
    [2706]
    , 1805 March 26.
    [2579]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to JOHN STEELE, COMPTROLLER OF THE U.S., 1799 December 30.; ALS. 1 pp. Photostat. Original owned by Frank Ix, Jr. #6820.
    William Short's U.S. Treasury account payable to John Barnes.
    [2580]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON to [?]., [1799].; ALS. 1 pp.; Barrow. Letterpress copy. Fragment. Last page only. Edgehill Randolph Papers. #5533.
    Wheat crop. Mentions Mr. Donald and Philadelphia.
    [2581]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON MATHEMATICS PROBLEM., [Post 1799].; AD. 2 pp.; Barrow. #2789.
    Solution of a geometrical problem from Jonathan Williams' Thermometrical Navigation.
    [644]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON to JOHN BARNES., 1800 January 1.; ADS. 1 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Bill of exchange to Tench Coxe. Receipted by Ezekiel Foreman for Tench Coxe.
    [2582]
  - JOHN WAYLES EPPES, Eppington, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1800 January 1.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Birth of Maria's daughter.
    [645]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Senate Chamber, to MR. PARKER, Franklin Court., 1800 January 13.; ALS. 1 pp., with attached address leaf. #8002.
    Houdon's equestrian statue of Washington in the Capitol at Richmond. Prices in Paris, Rome, and Florence. Mentions sculptor Ceracchi.
    [2582-a]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to CATHARINE CHURCH., 1800 January 22.; ALS. 1 pp., with attached address leaf. Hand franked and franked with ink stamp. #11245.
    Writes fond remembrances of her visits, and mentions his daughters Martha Jefferson Randolph and Mary Jefferson Eppes and that the latter has become a mother.
  - HENRY REMSEN, New York, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia., 1800 January 25.; ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Factors involved in low tobacco prices. Possibilities of peace in Europe. Subscription to newspapers and to prices current. Yellow fever epidemics. Gouverneur Morris' oration on the death of George Washington.
    [646]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to JOHN BRECKINRIDGE, Frankfort, Ky., 1800 January 29.; L. 1 pp. #38-414-a. Extract by N. P. Trist ca. 1830. Printed: Ford VI 416-419; L & B X 149-150; B of R VI 47 (letterpress copy in DLC).
    Kentucky Resolutions. Judiciary district for the West. Fear for republicanism in France. References to Napoleon Bonaparte and the Directory.
    [647]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to BISHOP JAMES MADISON., 1800 January 31.; L. 2 pp. Typescript copy. Original owned by St. George Tucker Grinnan. Printed: B of R VI 287 (MS. in DLC). #2118.
    Sends book by Joseph Priestley. Discussion of Augustin Barruel's Antisocial Conspiracy. Religious and philosophical doctrines of Wishaupt, Godwin, and Morse.
    [648]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to [WILLIAM] BACHE., 1800 February 2.; L. 1 pp. #38-414-a. Extract by N. P. Trist ca. 1830. Printed: B of R VI 20 (MS. in DLC).
    Importance of minority rights with majority rule. Danger of a military force. Bonaparte's overthrow of the French Constitution.
    [649]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON to THOMAS MANN RANDOLPH, JR.]., 1800 February 4.; AL. 1 pp. Fragment. Last page only. Photostat. Original owned by Harold Jefferson Coolidge; probably the last page of a letter in possession of MHi. #2873.
    Death of his coachman, Jupiter, at Fredericksburg. Orders for bottling cider. Mentions [Richard] Richardson.
    [650]
  - JOHN WAYLES EPPES, Eppington, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1800 February 7.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Maria's illness; attended by Dr. Turpin.
    [651]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to JOHN BARNES., 1800 February 10.; ADS. 1 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Bill of exchange to Maurice Rogers.
    [2583]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to JOHN BARNES., 1800 February 12.; ADS. 1 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Bill of exchange to John Hawkins.
    [2584]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to MARIA JEFFERSON EPPES, Eppington., 1800 February 12.; ALS. 2 pp., with attached address leaf; Barrow. Hand franked. #501. Printed: Randall II 535-536; SNR 263-264.
    Death of Maria's child. Failure of the mails. Plans to visit her on the way to Monticello. Inquiries about her health. References to Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr., and John Wayles Eppes.
    [652]
  - JOHN WAYLES EPPES, Eppington, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia., 1800 February 16.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Maria's illness.
    [653]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON to JOHN BARNES., 1800 February 26.; ADS. 1 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Bill of exchange to T. J.
    [2585]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to GEORGE WYTHE., 1800 February 28.; ALS. 2 pp. #4669 VOID. Photostat. Original owned by Henry N. Flynt. #4669.
    Parliamentary irregularities of Continental Congress and U.S. House of Representatives. Senate better. Encloses text of T. J. A Manual of Parliamentary Practice for Wythe's corrections.
    [2586]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON A MANUAL OF PARLIAMENTARY PRACTICE., [ca. 1800 February].; AMS. 4 pp. Draft. Fragment. Photostat. #3449-b. Original owned by Barron U. Kidd.
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to HENRY REMSEN., 1800 March 4.; ALS. 1 pp. Letterpress copy. Owned by Mrs. Edwin Page Kirk. #5291.
    Envoys at Lisbon. Sell tobacco to Mr. Lieper, not to French. Bordeaux and London prices. West Indies stock. John Barnes to pay draft. New York market. Congress to adjourn.
    [2587]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to GEORGE MEADE., 1800 March 13.; ALS. 1 pp., with attached address leaf. #10428-d.
    Explains how the proceeds from his annual tobacco crop are used to pay his supply merchant in Virginia.
  - THOMAS CARR. RECEIPT TO THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1800 March 23.; D. 1 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    For nails received from [Richard] Richardson by Carr and Thomas Bell.
    [654]
  - JOHN KELLY RECEIPT to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1800 March 24.; AD. 1 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Nails and brads delivered by R. Richardson.
    [2588]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to JAMES MONROE., 1800 March 26.; L. 1 pp. #38-414-a. Extract by N. P. Trist, ca. 1830. Printed: B of R VI 332 and II 111 (letterpress copy in DLC).
    Aversion to ceremony and wish to avoid newspaper publicity. Visit to Eppington. Progress of good sense and Republicanism.
    [655]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to RICHARD RICHARDSON, Monticello., 1800 March 31.; ALS. 1 pp. #3177. Owned by Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation.
    Sent box of plants and plaster of Paris. Instructions for construction at Monticello. Horses to meet him at Eppington. References to Davy Bowles, Nicholas Lewis, Reuben Perry, and Mr. Short.
    [656]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to MARIA JEFFERSON EPPES, Mont Blanco., 1800 April 6.; AL[S clipped]. 1 pp., with attached address leaf; silked. Hand franked. #38-576. Printed: Randall II 536-537; SNR 264-265. Pencil note: "Signature cut by permission of Mrs. Francis Eppes. Chas. W. Ward."
    Plans for trip to Monticello via Eppington or Mont Blanco. References to John Wayles Eppes, Francis Eppes, Martha Randolph, and Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr.
    [657]
  - JOHN WAYLES EPPES, Mont Blanco, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia., 1800 April 22.; ALS. 2 pp., with attached address leaf. Hand franked. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Maria's health restored. T. J.'s trip to Mont Blanco. Mr. Powell has agreed to go to Monticello (as overseer?). Reference to Miss Church. Death of [John?] Bolling.
    [658]
  - THOMAS MANN RANDOLPH, JR., to THOMAS JEFFERSON., [1800] April 25 [date received].; ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Suit against D. Mossis, involving James Ross, Mr. Skitt, P. Cours, and Colonel Morrir. Lilly's efficiency as overseer. Wheat crop, fruit, and sheep in good condition. [Richard] Richardson's work on T. J.'s apartment. Ursula's illness due to poisons of the "Buckingham Negro conjuror." Forwards sheeting samples.
    [659]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Philadelphia, to DEAR SIR., 1800 April 29.; ALS. 1 pp. #11145.
    Discusses arrangements to have horses sent from Monticello to the home of John Wayles Eppes, where he intends to rest for a few days.
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON IN ACCOUNT WITH JOHN BARNES., 1800 May 12.; AD. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Accountwith John Barnes, his commission agent and financial manager.
    [670]
  - JOHN BARNES, Philadelphia, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1800 May 24.; ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. McGregor Library, #123.
    Covering an account. Packages in the hands of Mr. Sheaff. Shipment of goods including china and oil. Eight per cent stock looking up. Purchase of government stock for William Short, Tadeusz Kosciuszko, and T. J. Medicine from Dr. Jackson. References to Mr. Stewart (Gilbert Stuart?) and G. Simpson.
    [660]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON IN ACCOUNT WITH JOHN BARNES., 1800 May 24.; ADS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Eppington, to JAMES MONROE., 1800 May 26.; L. 1 pp. #38-414-a. Extract by N. P. Trist ca. 1830. Printed: Ford VII 447-449; B of R II 111 and VI 332 (MS. in DLC).
    Disapproves of Union dinner. Disregard of Chase's accusations of atheism. Callender should be defended. Arrival of treaty from France. Reference to Dupont.
    [661]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON IN ACCOUNT WITH HENDERSON, McCAUL & CO., Manchester, England., 1800 June 1.; D. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Company's account, signed by James Lyle, covering T. J.'s payments from 4 March 1790 to 12 November 1798 on his bond.
    [662]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to MARIA JEFFERSON EPPES, Mont Blanco, Va., 1800 July 4.; ALS. 1 pp.; Barrow; free frank cut away; part of signature cut away. McGregor Library, #1223. Printed: Randall II 565; SNR 268.
    Dr. and Mrs. [William] Bache, and Mrs. Monroe are in the neighborhood. The "Forte piano" has arrived. Murder of Birch [Samuel Burch] by George Carter. Heavy wheat crop. Hopes for visit from Maria and John Eppes.
    [663]
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1800 July 26.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Bill of exchange for Van Staphorst & Hubbard. T. J.'s chairs misdirected to [James?] Brown for Col. [Samuel J.?] Cabell. References to Mrs. Ratcliffe and [J.] Letchworth.
    [664]
  - JOHN WAYLES EPPES, Eppington, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1800 August 4.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Francis Eppes' accident. Money required by Francis Eppes as security for Daniel Hylton. Maria Eppes mentioned.
    [665]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to PHILIP NORBORNE NICHOLAS. ALS., 1800 August 11.; ALS. 1 pp. Labeled "duplicate." #8404.
    Post script dated September 17 explains that T. J. believed original document miscarried, thus he his sending a duplicate. Architectural plan for Nicholas' house. Peter Carr's plan.
    [2588-a]
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1800 August 28.; ALS. 2 pp.; Barrow. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Forwarding an account. Discounts at the Bank of Pennsylvania. Bill of exchange to Van Staphorst & Hubbard for the credit of "P. M." Has acquired new house and store. Government stock for Tadeusz Kosciuszko, William Short, and J. B. Reference to Mrs. Ratcliffe, [John] Richards, S. T. Mason.
    [666]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON IN ACCOUNT WITH JOHN BARNES., 1800 August 28.; ADS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to JOHN BEELE BOARDLY., 1800 August 30.; ALS. 1 pp. Owned by George Green Shackelford. #3525-d.
    Mrs. Randolph, whom Boardly knew in England, holds marriage contract annuity payable by Peter Randolph, Peyton Randolph, and Philip Grymes. Peter Randolph's estate insolvent. Edmund Randolph is Peyton Randolph's heir. Suit filed against Philip Grymes, who can claim against Edmund Peyton, who cannot pay.
    [2589]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to SAMUEL SMITH., 1800 October 17.; ALS. 1 pp. Deposited by Albert H. Small. #12613.
    TJ has refused to accept a gift of two casks of wine from [Josef] Yznardi as he accepts no presents in office. TJ will pay for the wine and asks Smith to forward the casks to Gibson & Jefferson. TJ congratulates Smith on the "triumphs of republicanism" in Baltimore adding that the "spirit of 76 had never left the people...." He assures Smith that whether or not he wins the presidency the republicans will have a majority in the House of Representatives which "will keep the government from running wild...."
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1800 November 20.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    T. J.'s accommodations at Mr. Conrade's. Nautical Almanacs ordered. Pamphlet regarding C. C. P[inckney]. References to Messrs. Langdon, Baldwin, and Brown.
    [667]
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1800 December 5.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Price of handkerchiefs. Reference to Mr. Munn.
    [668]
  - THOMAS MANN RANDOLPH, JR., Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington., 1800 December 8.; ALS. 1 pp.; Barrow. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Requests that Samuel Woodson replace Nathaniel Perkins as postmaster at Goochland Court House.
    [669]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON IN ACCOUNT WITH JOHN BARNES., 1800 December 13.; D. 1 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
  - REMBRANDT PEALE to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington., 1800 December 17.; ALS. 3 pp.; address on verso. Endorsed by T. J. Owned by Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation. #5385-k.
    Wants to study in Europe as did John Trumbull. Prefers diplomatic post in France to one in Italy.
    [2590]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington, to JOHN WAYLES EPPES., 1800 December 23.; ALS. 1 pp. McGregor Library, #4979.
    Congress assembled. Housing costs more than at Philadelphia. Senate opposition to French treaty. Judiciary. Territorial governments. Votes of Vermont, Kentucky, Tennessee uncertain. Republican candidates have more votes than Federalists, Mr Adams and Mr. Pinckney. Mr. Powell builds nailery. Mentions Col. Burr, Maria, and Edgehill.
    [2591]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON IN ACCOUNT WITH JOHN BARNES., 1800 December 26.; ADS. 1 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON NOTES ON MILEAGES., [1800].; AD. 2 pp.; Barrow. #6225.
    Lists Monticello, Thornton Gap, Ruffner's, Cunningham's Mill, Rockfish Gap, Kennerley's, Madison's Cove, Jones's, Gilbert's, Narrow Passage, Rappidan, Robinson River, Brown's Culpeper Court House, Hedgeman River, Fauquier Court House, Germantown, [Pa.?], Widow Nevill's, West's Ordinary, Leesburg, Knowland's Ferry, Zane's, Winchester, Threetons, McCormack's, Harper's Ferry, Frederictown, [Md.?], Bentley's. Taverns listed, Leesburg: McEntire's, Indian King; Frederictown: Crush's, Sycamore Tree; Tawney Town: Mrs. Charlton's, Caleb's, Bacchus and Threetons; Petersburg: Kurtz's, The Swan; McAllister's Town: Rhenegher's; Yorktown: White's, Sign of the Lemon; Lancaster: Rickhart's, The Bear. Other towns: Alexandria, Colchester, Dumfries, Lansdowne, Elkrun Church, Piscotaway, Port Tobacco, Howe's Ferry, Port Royal, Bowling Green, Hanover Court House, Goodall's, Richmond.
    [2592]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON SKETCH FOR HOUSE AND DEPENDENCY., [1800].; AD. 1 pp. Fragment. Addressed on verso to T. J., Albemarle. #6225. See Nichols, N-465.
    [2593]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON [Monticello], to CRAVEN PEYTON., 1800.; AD. 1 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Plan for crop rotation--wheat, corn, and rye--for the years 1800-1804.
    [671]
  - PLAN OF SOUTH WING OF CAPITOL., [ca. 1800].; 1 p. ink and watercolor; 14 3/4" X 20 3/4" #5385-ap.
    Not executed by Jefferson.
    [N-390]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON NOTES FOR AN UNIDENTIFIED TOWN HOUSE., [ca. 1800].; Notes (2 pp.) and elevation in ink, plans of first and second floors and section in pencil. #10264.
    These notes are from ca. 1800, as the remodeling of Monticello is mentioned in the notes. These drawings, however, are not for Monticello, but for a house in town, probably Philadelphia. These drawings were evidently modified and submitted to James Barbour for Barboursville in 1817 as stated by Kimball.
    [N-4a]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON STUDY FOR ROTUNDA-PLAN HOUSE (PROBABLY FOR THE PRESIDENT'S HOUSE IN WASHINGTON)., 1800-1803.; Pencil, ink notes on reverse. Wove paper, probably CL, watermarked LONDON. 9 1/2 x 8 in. McGregor Library, #770.
    [N-409]
  - THOMAS MANN RANDOLPH, JR., Edgehill, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington., 1801 January 3.; ALS. 3 pp. #2439. Endorsed by T. J.
    Family's health good. Lilly's difficulties in hiring workers. Arrival of [John] Craven, new overseer. Work done at Monticello in clearing fields and in the nailery. Problems of handling the slaves. Mentions Mr. Powell and [Richard] Richardson, overseers.
    [672]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington, to MARIA JEFFERSON EPPES, Bermuda Hundred., [1801] January 4 [incorrectly dated 1800].; AL. 1 pp., with attached address leaf; silked. #38-576. Printed: Ford VII 477-479; Randall II 594; SNR 271-272.
    Visit to Mount Vernon. Enquiries about Maria from Martha Washington and Mrs. Lewis. Election of 1800. Colonel Burr's conduct honorable. Family meetings at Monticello and in Washington planned.
    [673]
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington., 1801 January 7.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Money for T. J. in check and cash. Reference to John Richards.
    [674]
  - THOMAS MANN RANDOLPH, JR., to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington., 1801 January 10.; ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Martha's illness. Lilly making up a gang. Clover, peas, turnips for the garden. Turnips required to feed sheep. Election to be decided in the House of Representatives. Reference to Cornelia Randolph.
    [675]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington, to JOSEPH ANTHONY., 1801 January 12; ALS. 1 pp.; mounted on card. #10428.
    T. J. writes regarding the payment he made Trumbull for a double pair of prints which he paid with an order on Leroy and Bayard.
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON IN ACCOUNT WITH JOHN BARNES., 1801 January 15.; AD. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington., 1801 January 15.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. McGregor Library, #564.
    Remittance to Gibson & Jefferson. Credit to William Short's account.
    [676]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington, to CRAVEN PEYTON., 1801 January 15.; ALS. 1 pp.; Barrow. Letterpress copy. Docketed by T. J. McGregor Library. #564.
    Requests Peyton to purchase shares of Henderson estate for T. J. in Peyton's name. Survey of line between T. J.'s land and the Henderson land. Equal vote for Republican candidates in the election of 1800. References to Colle, [John] Watson, and [Robert] Snelson.
    [677]
  - JOHN GARLAND JEFFERSON, Amelia, Va., to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington., 1801 January 17.; ALS. 3 pp.; Barrow. Endorsed by T. J. Carr-Cary Papers, #1231.
    Apologizes for long delay in writing. Offers to purchase his land near Lynchburg. Report that T. J. cast deciding vote in nomination of bankrupt son-in law of Adams, Joshua Johnston, as postmaster.
    [678]
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington., 1801 January 21.; ALS.1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    William Short's account.
    [679]
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington., 1801 January 24.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Sends two pairs of black silk stockings. References to Mr. Pickford and Mr. Latimore.
    [680]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington, to JOHN GARLAND JEFFERSON, Amelia, Va., 1801 February 1.; ALS. 2 pp.; Barrow. Letterpress copy. Docketed by T. J. Carr-Cary Papers, #1231.
    Refuses to sell Poplar Forest. Justifies his vote for Joshua Johnston. References to John Adams and George Washington.
    [681]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington, to MARTHA JEFFERSON RANDOLPH., 1801 February 5.; ALS. 2 pp.; Barrow. Letterpress copy. Docketed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Martha's illness. Anne Randolph's disposition. Election thrown into the House of Representatives. Comments on visitors who refuse to confine themselves to visiting hours.
    [682]
  - THOMAS MANN RANDOLPH, JR. to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1801 February 7.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.